[MUSIC PLAYING]
Hi, everyone. Mike Nelson here. This is Tom Servo.
Hi, everyone, and welcome to the Satellite of Love.
That's Mike Nelson, that's Servo, and I'm Cro T-Robot, Space Child. Hi.
Sure.
Eat me, Mike Nelson, for I am Space Child.
As you can clearly see by my eyes, I have been sent here by the supreme leader to enslave one and all.
Of course you have. Go ahead, Mike.
I am all powerful, Servo, those who defy me.
Oops, hang on. Yes, Commander.
What do we have?
I don't know. Did you ask Debbie?
Debbie?
Oh, no. No, that's Mike.
All right.
They want me to kill you. Hold on.
Just a minute, Mike.
What?
Oh, all right. I'll just come up there then.
Sorry, I'll be right back to enslave you all. Would you let Gypsy know, please?
Sure.
Okay. Well, we'll be right back.
I'm coming, Commander, you big stupid-y.
So, I checked with the great powers of the universe, and they said that since you are such brief, insignificant flickers across the grid of consciousness, you will have to-
Out of the eyes, Mike. He's nothing without his all-seeing eyes.
Out of vile jelly.
That wasn't real friendly, Mike.
Well, you're really annoying when you're omniscient.
I'm talking about the famous and famous of J&B novelty company, Flint, Michigan. A $1.98 apiece.
So does "all powerful" have to mean over budget?
Oh, the primate keeps calling.
Yeah. Yeah.
Oh, hi. I'm in a crappy mood today. You want to know why I'm in a crappy mood?
Because it's Lawgiver Days.
Ray!
Lawgiver Days!
Yes, human, in accordance with the Lawgiver, this time of year shall now be known as Lawgiver Days in order to honor-
You look pretty apparent, don't you? And for some reason this is the 32nd annual Lawgiver Days. I don't know.
All are ordered now by the Lawgiver to make merry and be lights of hearts under pain of horrible lingering death.
It's Lawgiver Days! Lift up your hearts and be glad, friends!
Well, human, have you finished your Lawgiver Days project yet?
You want to get busy, Mike? We're in charge of the bake sale for Lawgiver Days.
I didn't bake anything. Nobody told me.
Well, that's no excuse.
Well, actually, it kind of is.
Well, at least be a customer then, Mike.
Fine, I'll just have one of these kolaches here.
That's not a kolache, that's a kringle.
Well, then I'll have one of those.
That's a krumkaka. That's a pierogi.
That's a cornish pasky.
That's a perfiderole.
That's a pheffernus, a creamhorn, a krumhorn, a zeppole, a tiramisu, a baba rum, a zuppa inglés, a clair, a napoleon, a cannoli, a charlotte ruse, a baklava, a blint, a blini, a papadam, a naan.
Oh, nothing looks good. You know, I think I'll just have a slice of crow's mile-high meringue pie.
Oh, but it really is a mile high, Mike.
Oh, great.
5,280 feet straight up.
Yeah, well, I like meringues.
Well, I'd have to go up there and cut it, you see.
I'll wait.
Start climbing.
Oh, great.
Tell 'em so, no, stop it.
It's a really good race. I haven't gotten any of this stuff.
Like a canoe race, no, camber tossin'.
Listen, you clown! Get this through your thick skull!
I hate lawgiver days!
Stop this bloat!
Did I see someone not smiling during lawgiver days?
No, actually, I was just saying to Dr. Peanut how much I was enjoying lawgiver days,
almost beyond my capacity to enjoy.
Really? Which events did you enjoy the most?
Ah, let's see, the fire safety demonstration was very nice, of course,
and I certainly enjoyed the cakewalk.
Oh, the cakewalk was fun, wasn't it?
Yes, I do enjoy a good cakewalk.
There was no cakewalking! Babble, babble!
You haven't been enjoying my days at all!
Kill me, lawgiver! No other punishment will do!
You must kill me immediately and then kill me again!
Now that's lawgiver days.
Anyway, Mel Stone, your movie today is Mole People,
starring the stunningly annoying John Agar.
Enjoy! Or don't!
[Laughter]
No, no, crow, that's too big. Just a skosh.
No, my hips. Smaller, smaller, much smaller than that.
[Music]
Can I just get that to go?
Oh, we have movie time!
[Music]
You alright, crow?
I should have won a parachute.
Hey, the Earth from Shannon Lucid's point of view.
So, the Earth has neutral weather.
Bingo.
It's just a jump to the left.
[Music]
Ladies and gentlemen, it's amazing how much we know about the surface of our globe.
Your jacket, professor.
Men have progressively studied this.
Explorations have reached the north, the south pole.
They're reading relatively only a few square miles left of the surface of our globe that are not known.
Can you sign my drop sheet?
During the same years, men have reached out into the stars.
Three times further in your lifetime and mine, three times further into space than men have ever been able to go before.
Amazing knowledge.
Tell it, brother.
And of this, what's inside this?
This thing with the thing in the A.B.
What is there beneath our feet as we stand on the Earth?
No one knows, of course.
Science ponders about it and all men are curious, but no one knows.
Primitive man going into caves, reaching back and back and down and down, wondered what lay beyond.
And in terror he fled out.
Yeah, what a dope, huh?
He remembered strange sighs and noises.
Now you go back to Mesopotamia, the beginning of Western civilization, and you have the great hero Gilgamesh going down into the underworld.
So too were the Greeks. All down through time, religions of the past have postulated the existence of this inner habitable world.
All through the Middle Ages, people believed of something under the surface.
The great Dantie saw a great cone-like cavity stretching down to the very center of the Earth.
There's nothing new about this. It's as old as man, this belief that under the surface there may be areas inhabitable by man.
And in our time, in the last hundred years, have been a number of theories, very curious and strange theories about what goes on in the center of our planet.
Annoying theories.
This is a very famous and interesting and odd one. A soldier, a minor hero, the war of 1812, was a man named John Cleve Sims.
And he had a sudden idea that inside our world, like onion layers, there were globes within globes.
Five of them, some of them inhabited, and that if you were to travel up through the icy wastes of our world, the northwest edge of Siberia, you could go down through a hole and go successfully to these various...
Down, down, very nipple of the world.
Unfortunately, he was thoroughly obsessed with this, went around lecturing, and in fatigue died before he could make this experiment.
Jerks.
Here's another theory, much closer to us.
The clone half theory.
1870, about, a young American physician named Cyrus Reed Teed had a revelation.
We are not living on the outside of the globe, said Teed, but on the inside.
That when we think we're looking out at the sun, we're really looking...
Up Miss Johnson's skirt.
No!
Strange, strange...
Craziness.
A mind of man that tries to find answers to things that he can't understand. This was a theory by Karl Newport in Germany in the 1920s.
He fried egg theory.
He again imagines that we're living on the inside rather than the outside of the globe.
And here's a real sun, and a real moon, and then a rather shadowy and formless mass of...
Thingamabobs.
Electric potentiality with little bright sparks in it, and they give us the sense of our stars.
This turns out to be the correct theory.
Throwing this picture about to see, you'll see the culmination of a long series of such desires to look into the earth.
You know, he gets two million a picture.
One might well believe philosophically that some ancient culture, engulfed by a great and tremendous upheaval of nature, might linger on in some pocket of earth.
This is science fiction, of course. It's a fiction. It's a fable.
It's a fabulous, funny freakout.
For I think if you'll study this picture and think about it when it's over...
You'll feel dirty.
You'll realize that this is something more than just a story told.
It's a story botched.
It's a fable with a meaning and a significance for you and for me in the 20th century.
Thank you and goodbye.
Peanut nostrils, happy clams.
The really nutty professor.
Oh, these are the people who make that nice Mexican sauce.
Mount Pinatubo erupted yesterday, spewing movie credits all over the southern hemisphere.
Hey, Ward. And Alfred the butler.
Doesn't get any better than this, man.
With Rod Wedwing.
William Faulkner?
Scott Fitzgerald.
Laszlo Gorog. You guys were close.
Man, a plan, a canal. Laszlo Gorog.
And up from the ground comes a union film crew.
Sound and welfare reform by the governor of Wisconsin.
Tommy.
John Eggar finally gets to wear gowns.
Ah, St. Eggar, the patron saint of omelettes.
Oh, I get it. It's that special photography.
He's not a musician, but he's a hell of a good administrator.
He was the William Allen of his days.
Virgil Vogel, va va voom.
Vinny Vidi Vici Virgil Vogel.
Virgil Vogel, Vestal Virgin.
Well, that narrows it down.
How brown was my valley.
Hey, there's a kegger in Asia tonight, you guys.
Walking along district of basic Asian.
Building a deck on Asia.
Members of Cheap Trick plan their next move.
You know, this was Francis the Talking Mule's first film.
Watch eventually, Dr. Stewart. Come quickly.
Gary's pulling up the driveway. Everybody hide.
No Easter blowing in. Not gonna catch many yellowfin today.
Peace on earth is all it said.
Some sort of stone tablet.
It's the 23rd commandment.
Doing in this strata.
They couldn't form writing, but it is not possible in this part.
You mean it's not probable, LaBarge.
In archaeology, all things are possible.
Well, not really, no.
No matter where I serve by guests, they seem to like my kitchen best.
The fact is, we found it below the great flood level.
So it must be at least 5,000 years old.
Which would make it one of the oldest human records.
Older than Frampton comes alive.
Sumerian. It's a dedication of a temple or a public building.
Stewart, every time I think of how many civilizations have crumbled,
fallen apart, rotted from the inside or cracked from the outside,
I shudder when I pick up the front page of a newspaper.
A translation, Bentley.
I was being deep.
Sure.
First part reads, "I, Shahrukh, king of kings, son of Shahrukh."
I have three kittens to give away.
It breaks off there.
Shahrukh.
Well, that's a new one on me.
Mean anything to you, LaFarge?
Not to Bentley.
Do you remember the gilgabish tablets? George Smith's father?
Yeah, they told a legend about a dynasty that suddenly disappeared from the face of the earth.
Right. It also referred to a king of the dynasty, one called Shahrukh or Shahrukh.
Gucci, Gucci.
What does the rest of us say?
He who with malice destroys his faces or removes from its place,
this my sign at his station.
May he be denounced by Ishtar.
Yep, yep.
May his name, his seed in the land be destroyed.
Gotta run. Say hello to Marge and the kids.
Earthquake.
Incense around.
Earthquake. Shut up already. Damn.
Quick, build a door frame and hide under it.
I probably shouldn't have put the world's oldest record on a cheap card table.
[music]
Nice, they're making Lipton Sun tea.
Hmm.
We'll have to open new trenches tomorrow along the North Line, Jud.
Most of the old ones caved in.
That earthquake put us behind at least a month.
Ah, you know, Benjamin, we shouldn't complain about the work.
I think we were fortunate.
The epicenter of the earthquake was only 25 miles from here.
You think the goddess of Ishtar is punishing us for removing the tablas, LaFarge?
The inscription said, "He who removes it with malice."
But we aren't malicious, are we?
We want to rescue the Shahruh dynasty from oblivion.
That's what archaeologists are for, no?
Archaeologists are underpaid publicity agents for deceased royalty.
Sam Spade, archaeologist.
But it's my hand.
This shepherd boy found something.
What, another one?
This boy came a long way, Dr. Bellarmine.
Here you go, here's some lint, kid.
You buys your ticket and you takes your chance.
I believe in grabbing for the gold ring every time.
It's my left lung.
Hey, where'd you find this?
Kuitara, hi.
Hi.
Hi, friendly kid.
Kuitara, the epicenter of the earthquake.
Hey, I'm the guy who speculates wildly around here.
This is easy archaeology. People just bring you stuff.
It's either an offering to the gods or it's a gravy boat.
Here, diary. I can smell him nearby as he sits.
Quick, get the tiny zigzags.
It's a kind of moss that is native to this region.
It grows only on the rocks of Kuitara,
but not where the boy found it.
Much, much higher.
The earthquake must have dislodged it and rolled it down to the plateau.
But how did it get up on track?
Maybe Bentley has the answer. How's it coming, Rog?
It's an oil lamp, all right, shaped like a boat.
Hello from Bass Lake.
The grave figures are of a man, a woman, different animals and pairs.
They let Billy draw the runes this week.
The Sumerian version of Noah's Ark? Exactly.
The flood's been proven to be a historical fact.
Why not a Sumerian version?
According to the inscription, they got wet too. Listen.
We're really wet.
I, Sharu, king of kings, son of Sharuat.
From water I emerged.
I caused to embark within the vessel all my family, my relations,
my craftsmen and my slaves and the beasts of the field.
Oh, and my atrials.
Made my home in the ark.
We floated on the waves until we found the land of the snow
near the goddess of Ishtar.
At top of the mountain.
Made it, nah.
The Sharu dynasty was saved from the flood on Kuitara.
But was never heard of again. Of course not.
No one would look for human beings on top of Kuitara.
Hey, hey. Down, boy.
We're going to.
Still pissed.
It's impossible.
The summer is less than 20,000 feet.
It's treacherous. Always wind and snow.
Nothing's there. Nothing.
And we shouldn't be afraid of nothing.
You always twist what I say.
You're a dead man.
Free government cheese.
Gentlemen.
Start your hats.
Kuitara is a treacherous mountain to climb.
You think we can make it?
If we eat each other's flesh.
We shall establish three camps.
The fortress will carry enough supplies to establish a base camp
here at the foot of the snow level.
We will then climb to here,
which is 2,000 feet from the plateau on Kuitara
and establish a second camp.
The next day, we shall attempt the final climb.
Then we snowboard down Everest.
Always risking money because of a vague poetic inscription
on an ancient oil lamp.
I hate archaeology.
Don't you trust poets, old man?
No, I don't.
Schleman did.
He found the ruins of Troy by trusting Homer,
the biggest blabbermouth of all.
Oh, really?
My men are ready, sir.
Tomorrow morning, then.
But they're ready now, but, okay.
We're going to have to catch up because we're leaving.
They've been to Sam's Club of Asia.
We have to take all of his stupid Uriah Heep albums.
Agar and Beaumont are just packed in those boxes.
Nice culottes, Bullar.
He brought his lucky cinderblock along.
Check.
Four million in revenue bonds, and this is the bridge you get.
Shh.
Denny's.
It's a lot of mountain.
We're only going to the plateau.
Is that it on the right face, Nazar?
No, Dr. Stewart.
Tomorrow we may be able to see it if we keep to our schedule.
Then let's keep to the schedule.
Agar had to memorize his lines phonetically.
Will Steger leads another pointless expedition.
I think phosphates look pretty.
Help him, a tiny trout. I can't handle this.
Sure glad I didn't wear a dress.
Watch, they'll get crushed by a giant dog chasing a Frisbee.
Because it's there. What kind of an answer is that?
You know, this is where you appreciate good, solid music supervision.
Yeah.
See, they're bone chillingly predictable climb.
Completely on schedule.
They're going to find the frozen body of the lonely goatherd.
Do they have high altitude baking level yet?
I don't know.
My feet hurt. My boogers are sticking together.
Geez, they're only keeping this guy so they can hollow him out and crawl inside when he dies.
Hey, there's a ladder here, you guys.
We should have used it from the beginning.
You see, the groin pole was first discovered by the ancient Sumerians.
They're approaching the seventh green now.
Well, we tried anyway.
We'll make camp here.
And we'll dig our graves over there.
Well, the urine's as pure as it's going to get.
Peaceful looking, isn't she?
Well, peaceful-ish.
The thing that impresses me the most is the complete and utter silence.
You can almost hear it.
I could go on and on forever about the silence here.
Don't let her fool you, Mr. Bentley.
When she wants to, she can scream so loud as to make you deaf.
And you will hear her. And quite soon.
I think perhaps even tonight.
Let's move over to our Accu-Weather radar forecast.
(
Don't go, Freddy!
It's just plane nine. It's not that bad out.
Medicine bench and gasoline.
Yeah, I'm well down in front. My back teeth are chattering.
Cheer up, Jet.
This storm clears. We'll be on the plateau of Kui-Tao by tomorrow night.
Tomorrow night is 24,000 feet of thin air away.
It's not that windy.
Agar just tucked into the camp beans.
Avalanche.
No, thanks. Just had one.
Um, no fear.
I just realized my life is a lie.
Make something up. State it firmly, even arrogantly.
I'm still pissed at Beaumont.
This mountain's hundreds of square miles in area.
You're only occupying one square foot.
Sitting here is a lot safer than crossing Times Square.
At least in Times Square you got Sex World.
Whoa, he's got to cut his nails.
Yep, sure needed the snow.
Maybe we climbed right past the summit.
Stop looking at my pant leg.
Avalanche footage, run!
It's an avalanche! Come on!
You know, I just know somehow Balki is responsible for this.
A graphic depiction of lactose intolerance.
Mike, I don't love you anymore because the mountains are crumbling.
It doesn't matter.
Uh, all right. Hit me!
I can't. My arms don't work.
Well, then I guess I'll stay.
Hey, Mike, someone's calling on the hex field.
Mike!
Yeah, you want to get that?
I'm really terribly awfully busy right now.
Sure, fine. I'm your slave. Hang on.
Well, hello, it's me, the gesture professor from the beginning of the film.
I just came to update you on a few of the...
Down, down.
Hey, Mike, come on over here, honey.
No, it's me, the professor.
Down, down.
Fine, we'll come over there.
That's gonna be hard. I wish you could.
Oh, yeah, see you in a sec.
Now let's get this over with.
I hate those moments.
Well, he brought it on himself.
Does he realize how this kind of thing reflects on the entire satellite?
Probably not.
Sad, really.
Down, down, down. I'm going down, down.
Okay, stop it, Mike.
To see how the concentric layers...
Mike, stop it!
Jeez.
So, Mike, I'm a guy watching you do this impression.
Where do I laugh, Mike?
Mike, what makes it funny to me?
I don't know.
Uh-huh. Huh.
Well, you guys always get to do your funny little things.
You got your pierogies and your cream horns and your crum horns and everything.
And I don't say word one, but then I try to add a little levity and you jump all over me.
Well, maybe you're right, Mike, but come to us with that stuff.
Yeah.
Talk to us, 'cause this, this, this is no good.
So you want to finish your little skit, honey?
Uh, no.
Okay, come on over here, give me a hug.
Come on.
Come on, Mike.
Yeah.
There, good. Now say you're sorry to crow.
Sorry, crow.
Thank you, Mike.
Okay, why don't you just sit here for a little while and think about it, all right?
Yeah.
He's getting so big.
We'll be right down, dawg.
Mike!
You can stop laying on me now.
Well, the goddess of Ishtar isn't smiling so sweetly this morning.
She's retaining snow.
Look.
Taxi! Taxi!
Ah, never mind.
Guess there's a Mervyn's up there.
Mm-hmm.
The avalanche must have brought it down from the plateau.
Can anyone be living up there now?
In this thin air, it's possible to imagine anything.
Colony of mannequins, perhaps?
Kwai Chang-Kain's last journey.
You know, should anything happen to me, I suggest you pan-broil me with chanterelles and wood ears.
I'll be delicious.
It ain't no shocker. I love my blue buckas.
Jack Nicholson's house!
The ruins of a Sumerian temple are closed for repairs.
Look! There's a socks appeal and a Kinko's too!
Redevelopment opportunity.
Treasure these brief moments when John Agar isn't talking.
I've got rope if anybody needs rope.
Do you need some rope? 'Cause I got it here.
Gee, Sherpas really outdid themselves with this base camp.
Well, I'm going up to my room to see if they have satellite porn.
I don't understand.
They usually built their cities near their temples. Where are the rest of the buildings?
No, don't ask him a question.
Five thousand years is a long time.
It's not too late.
Oh, is it?
To make any sense out of all this is gonna take a while.
I think we ought to send Nazar back for his men and set up permanent camp here.
Is he?
Sir Bentley! Bellamy! Take a look at this!
I've got the weirdest hangnail!
At least she came packed in styrofoam.
Yep.
The goddess of Ishtar?
Right.
If found, please return to torso.
How did the inscription on the oil lamp go?
Do not light in heavy wind.
We floated on the waves 'til we found the land of the snow near the goddess of Ishtar.
Wait till Stewart sees this.
He's gonna blow chunks, man!
He's walking on right wrist.
See?
I already am falling!
I'm still plummeting! Be with you when I hit the ground!
Could you throw up the parking ticket?
Courtney Love is down there.
I can't see the bottom.
We gotta get down.
We gotta get funky.
Get your hopes, Nazar.
Let's take off all our clothes. Hurry!
I think you can see he's going down, down into the hole.
Down he goes.
Thank you, Mike.
Down.
Gotta believe that right now the other guys are contemplating cutting the rope.
Oh, definitely.
Should have brought more than seven feet of rope.
Why do I talk so much in front of those guys?
Every time I open my mouth, I just act like I know it all.
I just want to tell them how much I like them and stuff,
but then when I talk, I say all this stupid junk.
Gee, I don't know. Maybe I'm just kinda insecure.
But I do know a lot. Why shouldn't I talk?
Johnny Garlic, gentlemen.
I should have worn my Subas for this.
I'm gonna carve pompous things in this rack.
Oh, I think he's over-flossing.
Ew.
I mean, they should be grateful for my knowledge.
They say things I don't mind.
Now, what did they think was so fascinating about this?
They must have had really stupid focus groups back then.
Somebody said they wanted to see just how that knot was actually tied.
Yeah, it kinda wrecked the movie, not knowing.
Uh-huh.
Yeah. John A. Graham.
So, you know, I think I would rather watch David Crosby eat a McRib sandwich than watch this scene.
Yeah. Bozo in his later years.
So, this guy, Joseph Gershenson, music supervisor, had a pretty easy time of it here, huh?
Yeah.
Forgot his primatine missed.
So,
So.
Ah, no. This shot was featured in the film Visions of Light.
Oh, man. My dance belt.
I'll put the funny cat poster here.
Boy, Fonz didn't age very well, did he?
Shame.
Okay. Well, I could have done without that shot.
Yeah, me too.
Where the hell did I come from?
It's getting warm.
We must have come down at least a hundred feet.
It was ten, actually.
You gonna be all right?
Oh, sure. I'm fine.
Barney Clark, spelunker.
Ooh.
I thought the thumbtacks would hold.
Man, I gotta get away from that Nestor guy. All he does is talk, talk, talk, talk, talk.
Ooh.
Man, Ward got back.
Yep.
Michael Nesmith.
Yes.
Filmed in WedgieVision.
Wow.
This movie is just ropes and asses.
Okay, here comes something.
Now he's eaten by a mole.
God damn.
Just think of all he's saving up to say later.
All they brought were those little flashlights on their keychains.
Odd, I seem to be not talking right now.
Live from the Pantages Theater.
I found him!
I always find him in the last place I look. Ha ha ha.
I'll bring the dry vac.
You know, this is why the cleaver stopped at two children.
You okay?
Good one.
He didn't even make it to the second plot point.
You killed him, didn't you?
Should I have been untying the ropes on the way down?
Anybody need pelts down here?
You're gonna have to clean that rope with a Lysol when they're done.
Hey Hoser, better fix the Peggy.
Oh, right in the coconut. Wow.
Be right down.
Good job. Tighten the piton.
No, huh?
You kazoo tight.
There goes one lousy guide.
Sure fine guide.
We are trapped here. Shut up. Shut up.
But we've got high hopes.
Okay, well let's break this down into handleable tasks.
If we each take one rock per week...
If I left to go to the bathroom, you think I'd miss anything?
I don't think so. No, I don't think so.
Hey, this isn't a natural cavern.
It's a perverted, unnatural cavern.
You want it when?
You all right?
We are trapped here. No food, no water.
Oh, we got food, old man.
There must be another opening. Come on, let's look for it.
Did I mention that we are trapped here?
Another tunnel. Leads to France.
I heard Agar improvised this scene.
Don't take the camera off me. I'm dying.
Hey, I got the Amontillado.
It's baby Jessica. She's digging her own way out.
Yay.
I have to stop Christmas from coming, but how?
Ah, scary.
Take a look at the farge.
He's really getting to be a load.
I heard the vapors will have to call off the cotillion.
What's wrong?
It's the air. It's hard to breathe.
Give me a hand with him, Jeff.
I believe breathing is involuntary.
Just don't think about it so much.
Every couple of days you have to explain breathing to this guy.
Yep.
Very shrewd shooting in the dark.
No props, no set, no actors.
The Hardy Boys and their load.
Can I hold the flashlight for a while?
Please.
A Robert Motherwell painting.
She's light.
A load is hogging all the air.
Sounds like they're coming to the Hakowi Village.
The Hardy Indian Boy.
Hey, there is a place for fun and a holiday.
Hey, there is a place for fun and our lives.
What do you make of the light?
Probably some chemical in the rocks.
Pilgrim.
Actually, there's a big row of fluorescence up there, John.
There must be some rational scientific explanation for this.
I think the Elf Princess put it here.
Careful, he's outacting you all.
Lord.
Pilgrim.
It's an exact duplicate of the head we found on the plateau.
Here, gentlemen, is your city.
It's fabulous.
The city must have been built on it.
Rock and roll.
The thick crust of earth over a volcanic bubble.
Wrong.
Strong enough to support the city until an earthquake came along.
But made for a woman.
What we found on the plateau were the suburbs.
You're right. Look here.
It's the equivalent of your Skokie or your Downer's Grove.
Great, you just rubbed it all off.
The temple of Ishtar have I built with the stones of the mountain.
Why, yes, you have.
Sharu.
Shoo-pee-doo-rah-ru.
That's how the Sharu dynasty ended.
They all died.
They ran away from a flood right into an earthquake.
Shut up already. Damn.
The children of Noah survived.
The children of Ishtar died.
His head is shaped like a dust buster.
It's gonna be some history rewritten when we get out of here.
How do you know there's a way out?
There has to be.
We'll keep looking.
How long can we keep looking?
It's almost four.
We've been on our feet now over 15 hours.
Yeah, we gotta get some rest.
I've been speculating all day.
Well, this is as good a place as any.
I think I'll sleep forever.
Yep.
We all better lay very close for warmth.
How is it?
The load in repose.
The whole mountain were lying on my chest.
We're gonna get out of here.
Don't worry. Now get some sleep.
You might want to tell Elizabeth you're coming.
Somebody turn the walls off?
It's Gary.
A Starbucks employee was killed today in an avalanche of Guatemala Antigua.
What was that?
Can I have a little help back here?
I didn't hear anything.
You could just...
Come on, I just need a little...
I can't...
Nothing dangerous, dwarf, lizard, small bats, things like that.
I'm falling asleep.
Oh, you always know what to say, honey.
Well, them old people have jerry curls.
Venus did nothing old.
I ain't got nobody.
Shut up.
After the lovin' with the...
Like paper or plastic, sir?
Human rustlers grab three heads.
June, no, not tonight, honey.
Turning them into Jersey Kozinski.
These potholes, I'm telling you.
Well, that is a nasty sand trap.
You'll need to get some quick loft on this shot.
Wait, I forgot my rocks.
Down, down.
Down.
Well, no wonder I couldn't see.
They're like horses. You cover their heads and they're completely docile.
What do you think that was?
Who's got three nipples?
You slept with Madonna.
Hubba hubba.
Whoever it was needs a manicure.
It can be. It can be.
Well, might as well get up as long as we're awake.
Save your battery, Rog. There's no way out of here.
We were brought in. There has to be a way out.
Pilgrim.
You guys got any candy bars or crackers or anything?
I'm kinda hungry.
Would you say I'm dangerously thin?
Hey, there's an agate.
What do you think, Judd?
I'm no anthropologist.
I wouldn't know whether they were Cro-Magnon or Neanderthal.
Then why don't you just ask us?
I don't think an anthropologist could classify this one either.
That won't stop me.
All we can say for sure is...
Their crotches are smoking.
They walk erect.
Hey! Oh, I see what you're saying.
They have a skull large enough to house a brain with associative areas.
This is such good dialogue.
This one died as a result of a blow from a heavy blunt instrument.
See the owie?
That's the sign of higher civilization.
Deep.
Pinkly!
I had a bad dream.
What is it?
The old guy was originally cast in "Desperado."
Then Antonio Banderas got it.
Yep.
Don't move.
Terror elves.
Oh, you never would believe where those Keebler cookies come from.
Santa will see you now.
He wants us to go with him.
No, don't.
Well, we might as well, as long as we're here.
We'll make excellent fudge stripers.
It's got to be humiliating to be tortured by a Smurf.
I'm guessing that the door closes at the end of the scene.
What do you think?
Yeah.
I'm glad we came with.
The elves are pretty nice.
Hey, Sneezy, ever have rooms open up?
You guys know Data?
They're tan for English people.
It's an in-and-out burger.
I'm not sure.
It's beautiful.
It's an in-and-out burger.
You're doing a good job redeveloping the River Styx waterfront.
It's beautiful.
Well, he's late. I'm gonna leave.
Yeah, too.
Why, hello, young crow, stout mike, gypsy gal.
Well, I'm gonna tell y'all a story about a young bot named Tom
that he did on the Black Sea of Space for the last 500 a year
in the great tradition of the old Paladiers.
Oh, boy.
Strap in.
Dear God.
This should be an open D.
Well, I'm gonna take you down the river a song.
It's score year and ten when freighters roamed the sea
and this myth was king.
Well, there.
That doesn't quite work.
Well, there was nine and 20 years I was on the merchant marine
and billeted on the dam.
New strings or any ball super slinky, you know.
Anytime, burl Ives.
Got it.
Billeted on the Mary Ellen Carter bound for the dry tortugas
with a belly full of bismuth.
The crew of two scoring five, hail men and...
What's the score?
It's 20 now. Hush.
Go on with your story, Tom.
I'm trying.
Okay, true to the last as our medal was tested in the roaring 40s.
Lady Winter, she was angry as the rollers cracked rollers.
Sharpened and sharp. Stupid guitar. Stupid.
Come on.
Did you bring it up from the basement recently?
Maybe the neck is warped.
You should keep an orange teal in the cage.
Servo, you couldn't tuna kazoo.
These strings, okay?
Okay, wait, wait.
Okay, okay.
No, wait, okay.
Lady Winter, she was angry as the rollers cracked rollers.
Ow.
Oh, oh.
I'm sorry. Come on.
Forget it, okay?
Just forget it. Fine.
Well, don't worry, Servo.
You're still better than Marc Cole.
Oh, oh, oh.
We've got loser slots here. I think you'll have a good time.
It'd be safe to say we're down at the inner part of the world.
Stop.
Oh, God has granted us much fresh sewage.
Could you guys step it up a little?
We've got some other frost pick up.
Gentlemen, we've been captured by gay wrestling cheerleaders.
Hey, those guys can edge lawns in their spare time.
Oh, Hallarder's coming through. Excuse me, ladies.
Hallarder's.
No one has to tell Mr. Wayne about our little soiree.
Your salad tongs, sir.
Just do it.
In my hands I hold the magic eye of Ishtar.
The sacred weapon of Ishtar.
The golden rod.
Of Ishtar.
The secret of death.
Ooga, ooga, ooga, shotka, ooga, ooga, shotka.
Ah, let's just cash it. I don't feel like it today.
That's Alfred the butler, right?
Yeah.
He's modeled his hair after the Dickeyville grotto.
The world's most foppish Klansman.
Get out of my chair, Lieutenant Crownroast.
There, O King, are the evil ones who were captured by the beasts of the dark.
Oh, they're evil.
Bring them here.
Sorry, just don't like to be touched. I've got space issues.
Say, oh, hmm.
It's a race of albino Patti Labelle's.
Yeah, surface meat coming through. Look at it, ladies.
Who are you?
I'm John the pompous ass.
We are friends.
We are different from you, but we are your friends.
Kill them.
We speaks our tongue.
We come from a world where your tongue can be studied on ancient tablets.
There is no world beyond ours.
There is only heaven, where we lived a long time ago,
until we were expelled for our sins amidst thunder and fire.
Baptists.
This is the world, and we are its people.
You are not of us.
There is heaven, and only the gods live there.
Kiss my hat.
Would you tell us that you are gods?
Egar will.
I forgot to tell you, Carol called.
The greatest find of all time, and we're buried with it.
You're right. We should eat before the theater.
In the name of the king, I declare sentence upon you.
Here's the deal.
If you are evil spirits, you must be destroyed.
If you are mortal, as you claim,
our world cannot support you.
In either case, you must be destroyed.
Or accept workfare.
You will die in the fire of Ishtar.
Hey, that movie wasn't that bad. I mean...
Who will buy this wonderful feeling?
The load contributes.
Leslie!
He died like a man with a dress on.
Flap him, silly girls!
Paper in France, men.
Sashay, gentlemen. Sashay.
Don't look at my underpants.
Link, Julie, load.
- Stephanie! - I'm a load!
Oh, I'm not ready for my scene.
The light. Their eyes can't tolerate the light.
It's a pride of Dr. Smith's.
Help him up, judge.
And knock him down again.
Oh, our guy's lost in the semi-finals.
Stop! Stop! Do not run!
Stop! Do not run!
But they're mean and they hate us.
Oh, light that's slightly brighter than what we're used to. No!
The racist army is always undone by book dumpings and pantings.
They're a civilization of acts.
They're a civilization of elderly great-aunts.
We won the first round.
We better taunt them with "bawk, bawk, bawk."
If we just talk sports and home repair, we'll rule this world!
Data is down!
Look at him. No pigmentation.
Without sun or ultraviolet rays, they turn into albinos.
They make damn fine soldiers, though.
Pupils are enlarged to let in the maximum amount of low-intensity light.
He's pretty, though.
Optical nerve must be hypersensitive.
Am I here?
That's why they couldn't stand the light.
You diggin' me, Beaumont?
How'd they survive here?
What do they eat?
What happened to the mind, the memories of the past and the world of light?
Have they ever known a light-deck lunch?
So many questions.
And why is it necessary for them to kill us?
Look at us.
They have to kill us.
Because we made them doubt their world is the only world.
Their answer's the only answer's.
Thank you, Hannah Arendt.
Who's out?
Mmm, another Keebler. You don't even need to age these guys.
LaFarge, wait!
He's on full load now.
It's load overdrive for this guy.
LaFarge, wait!
You're the only load we have!
Wait!
Ah, that was just a little sprint load.
I think I'm loading quite well.
We must get away from them.
We have to get out of here.
If we go back to the temple, we are lost.
All right, LaFarge. All right.
Let's get you to bed.
You took the straps off, didn't you?
The three weird sisters.
Load, tell us some stories about other times when you were a major load.
You've been going down all the time.
It's getting hotter and hotter.
Yes, getting worse.
I agree.
What was that?
I don't know. LaFarge, you wait here.
John Agar said he didn't know something.
Unbelievable.
Come on, Jud.
We'll be right back.
Really, I can't imagine we'll be more than 15 minutes tops.
Eight weeks at the outside.
Attention shoppers, there's an unclaimed load in aisle five.
Listen.
Thrill as they listen really hard.
Marvel as they listen even harder.
Disney's dominatrix world.
Crack that whip.
Ah, Kathie Lee Gifford's garment workers.
We have much to learn from this culture.
We have no idea what we're supposed to be doing.
We pick up the dirt, you whip us.
We put down the dirt, you whip us. Come on.
This is all about whipping us, isn't it?
Dirt goodies and insect rolls.
Dirt goodies and insect rolls. There you go.
Well, you dug some good dirt yesterday. Here's two for you.
It's nice to know they serve light snacks in hell.
We need two here.
That guy just doesn't have skirt legs, you know?
I noticed the creatures are wearing trousers and little jackets.
My shiitake mine.
Reach for the stars.
Beast, God, get them.
Finally, something specific to do.
The button's jammed.
Stupid flashlight. I don't want it.
Come on, guys. Come on.
They were working.
Forget it. Come on.
Come on, Ken. Go on.
You have to. Come on.
Day 12, the expedition turns whiny.
So sad they're whipping their fellow day players.
Please, no stop. Wait, you're indispensable.
Well, okay.
Make a better beer stein than action hero.
Edouard's Shevardnazy hits the wall.
Oh, great holy movie. Please kill him.
Hello.
Help.
Hey, come on. I was clearing his passageways for CPR.
I'll be back. I'm gonna get some smokes.
They're noble creatures, aren't they?
He died as he lived. A total load.
Contents of load may have shifted during death.
Dear Lord, please take this, our brother, into thy loving...
I'm not dead.
...varily one of thy children...
...sweep him into thy tender...
...tender...
...frief.
...forever and ever. Amen.
What, John?
None of these lebards is at rest where he always lives.
In the world of the past.
But what a load.
I had a eulogy that was warm and glowing,
but you pretty much covered it.
Is the first stage of grief pure, unbridled joy?
Still feel like he's loading us down somehow.
Scenic design by El Greco.
Well, there's plenty of underground parking.
We're right back where we started.
There's bound to be a way out of here.
There's fresh air. It has to come from somewhere.
Why don't I go back to the river and try and swim out?
You know as well as I do that river runs underground from Mark.
In the king's name. Do not use the burning light.
Do not talk.
We come to you as friends.
I wouldn't count on that.
What do you want?
Since you have shown that you possess the divine fire of Ishtar...
You can cook tonight.
...the king is now convinced that you are holy messengers.
Are you speaking only for your king?
No.
The king's will is law for all.
He has ordered me to assure you of his friendship and to invite you to a royal feast.
It's a sumptuous brunch.
We're most grateful.
Climb under my skirt and follow me.
Where is the absent one?
He was called back to heaven by Ishtar.
He's gonna charge my nipples weep for you.
Follow me.
Do you want chicken or fish?
Juice or beets or muffin with butter?
And why did Ishtar send you to our kingdom?
It was a monster, Marsh.
See how you live?
To learn of your needs so she can help you.
Does she not know us through our prayers?
Does she not reward us for our prayers?
Does she not reward us for our sacrifices?
Three emo Phillips.
Does she not see us with her all pervading eye?
We were wondering if we could eat now.
Then you will see.
Our kingdom is your home.
And here's Kitty Carlisle with the soup dish.
Hi, Susie.
Hey, Debbie.
Hi, Verna.
Bull jerky and fresh Ottomans.
Mushroom.
See, I know something too.
Why not?
It's one of the few things that can grow without the sun.
Show them enough of your crap on it, anything will grow.
God's worthless vegetable, the mushroom.
Come here.
Your aunty maim privileges are revoked for a month.
Nah.
David Sowell's favorite movie.
Eh, cruel, but she did drop the mushroom.
Do not interfere.
The king's will is the law.
The fire of Ishtar is the law.
So be it.
You win everything.
Say, honey, can I get a fresh cup of coffee?
You have fondness for her, have you not?
Yes.
She belongs to you.
Go.
Okay, but I still have a lot of friends.
Okay, but I still want my tip.
The gods do not favor trading human beings.
Human?
She is a mocked one.
Mocked one, like a mustang?
Are there many like her?
No.
Rarely is one born with the mark of darkness.
Any others, like yourselves?
How many are there?
Twice and a half times 60.
That's not very many.
It is a sacred number.
The highest number that our sacred food can nourish.
What do you do when your population exceeds that number?
We kill them.
We sacrifice them in the fire of Ishtar.
It's really cool.
You should watch.
The light of which you possess within that cylinder.
Sir, there's a little problem with the visa card.
The beasts of the dark have desecrated our dead.
They took the body of the god that was slain by the intruders.
When they were finished with it, they left it in the tunnel.
All the flesh had been torn from the body.
You have apprehended them?
I have, O priest.
So what do we usually do here?
Kill them.
Oh, and we need the pan on your head for dessert, sir.
Let us now bless the spirit of the earth.
Yeah, okay, I guess I'll do it.
Ishtar has given us the food of the tunnels,
the fish of the river, and the sacred milk of the goat.
Again?
Above all, we glorify Ishtar
for giving us power over the beasts of the dark
that they may till the earth beneath us.
So the Charo king of kings, his children and his children's children,
may live in strength and rule the world.
So did.
And a special intention for Agnes Pankratz,
who's having surgery this week.
Well, if there is a way out, we'll never find it.
Not without help.
You mean the albinos?
No.
Do I have to guess?
Surely you don't expect the beasts of the tunnel to help us.
Why should they after what's been done to them?
Five thousand years of slavery,
a planned degeneration has turned men into beasts.
There's no help there, Jeff.
Okay, you were the kool-aid and you were the banjo, right?
Thank you, Adele.
Lie down, my lord.
Adele, I am drinking my milk, okay?
Go right ahead, Rog, don't mind me.
I'm gonna go whip the mole.
I will watch you while you're away.
Away?
In your dreams.
What about you?
When do you sleep, Adele?
Or do you?
I sleep when my sleeping time comes.
Your sleeping time?
But how are you able to tell?
Whenever you speak.
And my heart beat.
One, two, three.
But you're not counting all the time, are you?
Yes, I am, six, seven.
I just feel it all the time.
What happens when your heart beats faster?
It matters not.
It is my heart.
It is my time.
We've gotten off on a weird tangent here.
Okay, Dad, you talk to me.
Okay, Dad, you'd better go home.
This is my home.
The king has ordered it so.
Oh, never mind the king.
You're free to go, understand?
Look, amps gray.
What is free?
If you wish to go, you go.
And if you wish to stay, you stay.
That's being free.
Then I am free.
Because I wish to stay.
Don't! No!
But you're in danger.
I'm John Agar.
Danger? Why?
Because I have bouts of pomposity.
Because we're different than your people.
They fear us and may try to harm us.
You're different too.
And if you're with us, it may remind them.
Um, you really lost me there.
What are you going to do?
Try to get back to our world.
There's nothing beyond darkness, my Lord.
Are you sure of that?
Have you never in your life heard of a world of light above the darkness?
Have you never been mellow?
No, my Lord. Never.
Except once in a Moody Blues song.
Well, then let me tell you about it.
Um, could you not?
The world of light changes color with every heartbeat.
They're mighty rivers.
Some folks like the summertime and strolls all around.
And then there are the cities.
Beautiful cities.
Quad cities.
Filled with many people, like you and me.
You're speaking of heaven, my Lord.
And I've heard, "Ooh, heaven is a place on earth."
Maybe I am.
Suddenly Susan is on.
A bubbling crude.
You guys really need to be shirtless.
It's about 60 degrees in here.
This is where they crank out the cheap souvenirs.
Over here's the branding tank.
You here for the sous chef position?
Well, that's one way of doing it.
Wrong.
What is it?
Steam from an underground spring?
No, no.
I'm not sure.
Steam from an underground spring?
Something hotter than that.
Fudge.
Remember, I know everything.
They killed Fazibear.
Three of these went out.
Your tan hides with tannic acid made from tree bark, right?
What do they use?
Want me to ask them?
No, not now.
Let's go.
Did I miss a joke?
What the hell's going on here?
Mark 7, Mark 7.
Mark 7 Productions, Mark 7 Productions.
Eh, let's go to old mole town.
The Egyptians were able to weave very fine materials out of wool.
Jeez.
The stuff they're waving here looks like burlap.
The finer cloth is loomed by the priests.
One of their trade secrets.
So you read the brochure.
Big deal.
I'd like to get out of here.
But I'm not done droning yet.
And action.
And that is not all.
The king has shown weakness and poor judgment.
He believes in the divinity of these intruders.
Dealing with the divine is our office.
We abandon the smallest particle of it to outsiders.
Our position will soon come to naught.
But are these outsiders not divine?
No, they are mortal.
Do they not eat when they're hungry?
Do they not sleep when they are weary?
When the gods attack them.
Did not their faces show the fears of mortal men?
But do they not possess the power of heaven?
That's a good point, Gary.
The cylinder they carry possesses it.
If you had that cylinder, or you, or you.
But not you, Tad.
You could use it too.
And if it is the power of heaven,
is it not we who should possess it?
And use it to control the beasts of the dark, the people, and...
Yes, if need be.
Even a faltering king himself.
Sir, what about the parallel parking resolution?
You will therefore follow these intruders
forever they may go.
And bring me that cylinder.
And pick me up a frappuccino too.
Where'd you put those Christmas decorations?
Here's something.
No, that's not it either.
Uh-oh, does that look like the dishwasher's leaking?
That's hopeless, Roger.
Not as long as we're alive.
Oh, sue me.
Kristen McNerney looking wonderful in a Vivian Westwood.
He's a transvestite.
He likes to wear pants in private.
We're free.
It was so easy, really.
Well, that's another fine mess you've gotten us into, Stanley.
Why don't we just give up and apply for Sumerian citizenship?
I don't like mushrooms.
Oh, now, don't complain, Rog.
Last night we had cave rats for dinner.
You got cave rats.
Now, why don't we settle down?
Start a family.
Especially you.
Why, especially me?
Well, there's a doll.
Just imagine what some future archaeologist would think
if they happened to rediscover this world.
And the wild theories they'd concoct in order to explain
the presence of dozens of little Bentleys speaking Sumerian
with a Harvard accent
and playing baseball in front of the Temple of Ishtar.
The Ishtar and I in champions is a little mushroom.
Look out, Harold Lloyd is behind you.
Come on.
Glad I had my peripheral vision removed.
My plan is going swimmingly.
Not everyone can wear a snood.
They're being transferred to the Hall of Goats.
You should never have goats and whipping in the same scene.
I had a burrow, like, from three miles over to get this job.
I'm not even sure it's worth it.
The mole people need Cesar Chavez.
All right, Ted.
Nothing personal, just the business.
Is all in order?
In order, Captain.
Shall I feed them?
They're getting weak.
You have your orders.
They're not to be fed until you're told otherwise.
Yes, Captain Fingerhead.
Man, I'm good at what I do.
Hi, can we borrow a goat?
There's been an alarming number of footballs
disappearing from this place.
Gods, six-day lashes.
Make them long, beautiful Maybelline lashes.
It's always upsetting to see elves whipping.
Well...
Come on, I can take a brownie. I've done it before.
Please, don't interfere.
The Beast has committed a crime.
He was hungry.
My orders are to keep them hungry.
Captain, look.
There's a bathroom stall open now.
Do you realize you're bringing disaster on our heads?
And yours too?
Come on, people are pushed. You want some, huh?
I'm just so tense,
I'm going to go whittle some napkin rings to the lights.
Cassius, Anthony,
where's the Ides of March dinner?
There's sand up my skirt,
and I'm not wearing any underwear.
Oh, the pain.
I'd rather be in some dark hallow
Where the sun don't ever shine
Okay, that's good.
Brought you a big delicious pan of smarmy.
Boy, you're really bad.
Did you learn that song as a child?
I'm tuning it.
I did not learn it. I found it.
(singing)
It's beautiful.
As beautiful as you are.
No, I'm a marked one.
The priest said so.
They're so right.
You win.
It's okay.
It's not only the color of your eyes,
your hair, your cheek that mark you.
It's the color of your spleen.
But your heart also
beats with tenderness.
The love of your ancestors is there.
Oh, I do not understand.
Are you high or something?
Well,
If somebody has hurt and his hurt gives you pain,
or if somebody has joy and his joy gives you pleasure,
that's love.
There's a booger blowing in and out of your nose.
Adele,
do you believe as your king believes
that I'm one of your gods?
No, my lord.
Our gods are always angry and give orders.
Oh, she's Catholic.
You smile.
If I ever get out of here,
into my world.
The world of light and flowers?
Will you come with me?
Yes, my lord.
My lord.
Can you zip me?
What is it?
The king wishes to see you at once.
He can't remember a line from Carousel.
Thanks for the bucket of cold water, Clorox face.
I should have cut this off a long time ago.
It's new in the hollow tree, you freaks.
The captain of the gods has been found murdered.
The beasts of the dark have done it.
It is possible they intend to revolt.
What about your guards?
Cowards.
Hey!
They tremble at the sight of their own shadows.
We do not want unnecessary bloodshed.
We need the beasts.
But with your cylinder of fire,
you could bring them under control.
Oh, I thank you.
Oh, you mean the flashlight.
Okay.
We will not take part in any plan to punish your slaves.
Actually, I was kind of looking forward to that, John.
They are against us.
They are evil.
Ishtar has sent them.
I say to you that she is not.
Take their magic cylinder away from them
and you shall see then that they are powerless.
And we will have their power.
No, Elinor.
We will not challenge Ishtar.
Oh, fool.
Have the gods arrest three of the beasts
and beat them until they are dead.
Oh, Pilate's favorite.
What I wouldn't give to be spat upon.
This is unpleasant.
Just pretend it's Adam Sandler.
Suddenly it's the same.
Suddenly it's great.
And that's for Billy Madison.
Let's melt some elves.
They make the French army look stalwart.
Come on, plenty of decel for everybody.
No, this makes my dress hurt.
The fire of Ishtar.
And so are we.
As long as they think we're armed, they'll stay away from us.
Walk this way and look like you've got batteries.
Come on, help me with these chains.
You're gonna release them?
We can't leave them here.
They attacked us the last time.
The guards forced them to.
The guards are the John Brown of the mole people.
So we're in the Green Giants' protective cop on their backs.
Go.
You're welcome.
Hey, thanks you guys.
If you ever need any earthworms or tunnels, you just let me know.
Oh, uh, me and the other moles we went in on a little gift for.
Well, any profound insights, John?
They're really jello mold men.
May your holes be long and deep.
He was trying to say something.
Yeah, I think it was...
They don't have the power of speech, but they can read.
[
While digging a new foundation, I've stumbled on fascinating evidence of an earlier me.
A creature that existed hundreds of years ago, right here, right where we are now.
That would be you.
Exactly.
And through rigorous archaeology, I'm able to describe something of the life that this weird being might have led.
And yet there are so many questions, like how did this proto-Kro fashion this crude likeness of himself?
Brush that off, will you?
Yeah.
That's a Polaroid of you.
So, so, so, something, a mate perhaps, took this Polaroid.
What does that indicate about?
Well, it looks to me like you just held the camera out at arm's length and took the picture yourself.
Another possibility, yes.
And yet, as we dig deeper into the timeless eons, we find...
Gaily decorated fabric.
Wow.
Seemingly very important to the culture or the tribe or herd or...
A kro, it was you. It was simply you.
Yes, but can we ever really know?
For now, I'd ask us to close our eyes and imagine this thing, this, this beast.
This is you.
Crouched on his haunches in the night, terrified of the howling predators.
Ah-hoo!
Honey.
And yet with some dim flicker of intelligence, this...
You.
This me or me's wandering these very halls, groping for meaning, carving fertility symbols.
Kro, Kro, it was you. It was simply you.
You lived here for 500 years by yourself.
But you know what that would mean? I lived here by myself for 500 years.
Mike, it's you!
Yeah.
And Servo!
Oh, how are you guys?
Good, pretty good.
I remember now. So what in the name of heaven was I doing with myself?
Did I do anything but eat nut goodies for 500 years?
Well, you did make this nice fertility symbol.
What'd you need that for?
I don't know. Apparently I couldn't conceive at some point.
Oh, with a comb?
Oh, look at this mess I'm sitting in. Give me a sponge, will you?
We'll be right back.
... turned her face away from us because we have sinned.
The intruders are the sinners, and we are to starve because of them.
They are behind the rebellion.
It is they who encourage disobedience so that the beasts of the dark do not produce enough to feed us all.
If we cannot produce enough food, we must reduce our population as it is inscribed on the sacred stone.
We will offer them in sacrifice to our goddess so that the others can live.
They could just get vasectomies.
Excuse me, my story's on.
In my hand I hold the golden rod.
Whoa!
The secret of death.
The sacred barbecue time.
For death shall appease Ishtar through the spirit bride of sacrifice.
Ishtar, who is married for life to the spirit of our world, to the glory of death.
Northwest Obe-yea.
Oh yeah, work it baby, that's it.
Shake your moneymaker.
Cindy Lou Who? No!
So she's the best they could do, huh?
Mm, no. Think of math.
Knoblocks betting 383.
And away we go!
I shouldn't have gone out for sacrifice.
She didn't really practice at all.
And she wasn't chosen for the sacrifice because?
Haha, I'm not being sacrificed. Haha, Sherry.
The Linda Hunt modern dance troupe.
Oops, I tripped, sorry.
Thank you, Bjork.
Check it out. Check it out. Check it out.
This is the Jerry Garcia guitar solo of Liturgical Danes.
She has a Romanian gymnast look.
Now her head starts spraying water and kids run through it.
Amateur night of the gods.
This has got to come across as kind of an insult to the gods, you know?
Ishtar's gonna fry somebody's ass for booking her.
Ishtar's gotta love that.
Ladies and gentlemen, in the junior dance competition, Shelly.
Thanks, baby.
I'm sorry, I apologize. I booked her.
If Shelly's done drinking in the praise, could we get sacrificed in the fires of Ishtar, please?
No, they're not really sacrificing much with the sacrifice.
Here you go, sir. Light starch, perfume-free.
You were sneezed in it last time.
Uh, sir? Sir? That's the broom closet, sir? Sir?
Oh, jeez. Who forgot to clean out the last sacrifice?
Ah, Helen Mirren volunteers to go first.
Appetizers for the gods.
Kal-Gan, take me away.
Willy, don't go in there.
Looks like Al Lewis in a long wig.
The death of Shirley Manson. Stupid girl.
Susan, don't throw my sweater on the floor.
Are they in? Everybody in? Huh?
He only has 30 seconds to punch the code.
Bye-bye now. Safe home. Call us from Grandma's free cars.
I'm blind! I'm blind! Oh.
That's one of the modern clocks. You got no idea what time it is.
Now we baked some sacrifices earlier.
Oh, crap. The pilot light went out.
Get some garbage bags.
Get the holy drippings and make the sacred gravy.
Oh, boy, I'm glad it's Friday. I'm already sipping my first margarita, I tell you.
It's got one of those "Why bother?" mustaches.
It... don't... No, forget it.
They're done. They're 140 degrees at the bone, sir.
Now we apply the holy solar cane.
I want it so badly for George Hamilton to like me and I...
Don't you move over. You always steal the covers.
Oh, and I aerated the lawn.
I have something to show you, priest. No! Please come with me.
Yeah, I got about halfway into it and I can't get the rest in.
The instructions are really confusing. I just want you to take a look at it, see if you can see what's up.
I'll take a look here. See what you got.
Oh, yeah, just toenail that in there.
Oink. Oink?
Oink? Oink?
Okay, well, thanks anyway. I'll just do what I was gonna do. I'll just follow the instructions.
They were gonna strip it and I was thinking you could take a look at it. I thought they might mess it up.
You woke me up for this.
And he is dead, as we shall soon be dead if we do not deal with the intruders.
What do you advise? Give me freedom to act.
Do you have it? Destroy them!
And don't interrupt my bridge club again.
Did you ever hear of anyone smoking dried mushrooms? Sure.
Oh, nothing. Skip it.
Well, what a pleasant surprise. Where'd all the food come from? Slaves back at work?
I don't know, my lord. The food keeper was very generous.
Delicious. Sarcasm doesn't help, sir.
Sit down, Adele. Oh, no, I couldn't. I just had a half a clean peach yesterday.
Why don't you eat? Royal food is not for servants.
Haven't I told you before that you're not a servant? Now go get me a beer. Yes.
And what else have I told you? That you follow me for my own safety?
That I'm just like you. Except for table manners, apparently. Right.
Now eat. In your presence, my lord. I cannot eat.
What's the expiration date on this rat fat?
Tell her.
Their chef is Stanley Owsley.
My lord. My lord.
They've been eating champagne corks.
Just put that anywhere. Thank you.
Honey, honey, we have company. Honey.
Cecil.
I should dress it like a good John Agar fight sequence.
I'll just, uh, jot over here.
Ew, ick, there's gum on it.
A flashlight. Now all we need is a tent, some s'mores, and some outside.
Diamonds, daisies, mole men, that girl.
I left my wife and forty-nine kids on the verge of starvation with only one hamburger left.
Her left. Left. Right. Left.
So the bat. I just lapped myself.
Grace called in sick, and I am really in the weeds here.
How's the dirt harvest coming, guys?
She stumbled into the Hormel meat packing plant.
Earth's pores need cleansing. Deep cleansing.
Honey, I told you not to visit me on my shift.
All whippers up front.
Got one.
Union! Union! Union!
Union!
Meet you in the break room, Ted.
Yep, see you in there, Tony.
Oh, great. And I'm shift leader.
Hey, we could whip each other.
Okay, who's got the packing slip on these guys?
No. No, please, no. I need my bandeau soleil.
Out, out you pixies, go.
Oh, no, I surfaced in the cat box.
Pizmo Beach and all the clams you can eat.
Ah, Wisconsin bar at midday.
Hey, you guys can just go home. I've got like an hour of paperwork to do.
Really ought to have those moles looked at.
Thank you.
Kill them.
Quick, run hoses down their holes.
Folks, don't have a dirt basement if you have man-eating moles.
Dare I say I'm in charge? I'm in charge.
It's not a very good wig.
Oh, Mr. Trysdale.
With nothing to fear, I have the burning light.
Well, maybe we have a little to fear.
Mole cam. Actual mole footage.
This is for all those years of whack-a-mole.
Do you want a piece of me?
Well, doesn't this just frost your beans? Oh, hello.
Evidently the king is completely titular, huh?
Bring in the stunt, king.
You guys, no insurgencies in the house.
Um, does anyone want a pop? I'm going to the fridge.
Oh, it's so nice. Let's take this outside.
Please, no. I'm seeing a nightcrawler.
Great. Why did I bring democracy to the moles?
Excuse us, ma'am. We'll take care of this for you.
Ugh, and they call me the Marked One.
Oh, no.
The rumpus room.
Wait.
I'm the door jam.
Where do I go in an earthquake?
I forgot my Lancome and my journal.
Lucy.
She is a monumentally stupid person.
It's ironic, because remember how she hated pillars?
Okay, here's one.
Could you get me another pillar?
You had so much to talk down to me about.
Be with us next time when they discover the pocket gopher people.
Later, when Marlon Brando hops on his treadmill.
All the dirt is going down, down, down into a hole that goes down.
Then let this be a lesson to all of us.
Never attempt to discover ancient civilizations.
Stick your head in the sand.
Don't go chasing waterfalls.
And if there's any changes in your mole, please check with your doctor.
I'm going to order the John Agar encyclopedia set.
While the Indian boy.
ATN means load in French.
So does La Farge, ironically.
Load, load.
And no one ever trusted a John Agar film again.
The end.
No, no, no, no. I thought about it, Mike.
And it's only logical there's a series of concentric holes beneath the ship
containing diverse civilizations.
Uh-huh. Sure, Crowe. Right.
What? You're too afraid to pop open a floorboard and see?
No, I'll check it out. I'm game. All right.
There we go.
Fine. Go ahead.
Some crowbar. I'll just pop a floorboard and test your little theory.
Oh, you're the marked ones. I sentence you to death.
Yes, yes. By all means, go away.
Oh.
All right. Well, I think I can take care of this with a flashlight.
Yep.
Oh, and it's a bar of the stars.
Get down, Junior.
Scram.
Wow. Right. Okay.
I told you.
Well, we better call Orkin.
And as the 32nd annual Lawgiver Days draws to a close,
the firework fades in the distance,
we may look back on all the fun we have shared.
And as is our tradition, we present to you, Miss Lawgiver,
a small token of our veneration of sequisness, Howard.
And he's mute, too.
So, what does he do?
Well, I don't know exactly. Well, he's a gift.
Howard. You, Howard.
Howard. How...
And what am I supposed to do with a beefy, virile, muscular, sweaty,
servile, well-oiled hunk?
Oh.
Oh, Howard.
(music)